菲比  来了
Here you go, Pheebs.
谁要吃我的特制巧克力蛋糕
Who else wants one of my special home-baked brownies?
-我要一块  -我要
- I will have one. - I do.
-算了  -不要了
- That's okay. - I'm not having one.
不是  是我牙痛
No, no. It's just my tooth.
-好  -我要一块
- All right. - I'll have one.
怎么了  你要看牙医吗
So what's matter? You need a dentist?
我认识一个好医生
I've got a good one.
谢了  我也认识一个  只是我不能见他
Thanks. I have a good one too. I just can't see him.
这就是隐形牙医的问题
See, that is the problem with invisible dentists.
你为什么不能去找他
Why can't you go to him?
因为我每次去看牙医  就会有人死
Because every time I go to the dentist, somebody dies.
真诡异  我每次去看牙医
That is so weird. Because every time I go to the dentist...
都会偷看医生的胸口
I look down the hygienist's blouse.
菲比  你说什么
Phoebe, what...?
什么
What?
是啊  第一次是玛丽阿姨
Yeah! First, it was my Aunt Mary.
然后是我的邮差约翰
And then there was John, my mailman.
然后是我的牛仔朋友  艾拜诺·巴伯
And then my cowboy friend, Albino Bob.
这些人真的都死了吗
And all these people actually died?
对  当我坐在诊疗椅上时
Yes. While I was in the chair.
所以我都自己保健牙齿
That's why I take such good care of my teeth now.
不是为了口腔卫生  我用牙线是为了救人
You know, it's not about oral hygiene. I floss to save lives.
菲比  拜托  你没有杀人
Pheebs, come on, you didn't kill anybody.
只是这些人死的时候  你刚好去看牙医
These people just happened to die when you went to the dentist.
这只是巧合
It's just a coincidence.
你去跟他们说啊  哦不行  他们都死了
Tell that to them. Oh, you can't! They're dead!
甘瑟  谢了
Thanks, Gunther.
可以给一张纸巾吗
Can I get a napkin too?
你还不够称心如意吗
Like you don't already have everything.
菲比  你痛得很厉害
Pheebe, you're in pain.
去看牙医吧  快去吧
Would you just go to the dentist. Just go.
好  但如果你是下一名受害者
Alright, fine. But if you're my next victim...
别化身成厉鬼跑回来  把我吸进电视里
don't come back as a poltergeist who sucks me into the TV set.
保证不会
I promise.
但还是欢迎你来找我
Although, don't feel like you can't visit.
钱德勒在吗
Hey, is Chandler here?
不在
No. No, he's not.
乔伊看到珍妮斯跟前夫接吻
You guys, Joey just saw Janice kissing her ex-husband.
什么
What?
你要怎么办  要怎么告诉钱德勒
So what are you gonna do? How are you gonna tell Chandler?
我一直在想这件事  最好的办法就是
I was thinking about that. I think the best way would be...
不要说
to not.
乔伊  你不能保密
Joey, you can't keep this to yourself.
既然你知道了  就得告诉他
If you know about this, you have to tell him.
那他就完了  真的完了
It'll kill him. I mean it'll just kill him.
等我去看牙医吧
Well, you can wait until I go to the dentist.
或许我会了结他
Maybe I'll kill him.
丑裸男在睡吊床
Ugly Naked Guy's using his new hammock.
好像培乐多玩具猪肉工厂
It's like a Play-Doh fat factory.
我要去看牙医了  听我说
I'm going to the dentist. So listen okay?
小心会让你们掉进去的东西
Just be on the lookout for anything that you could fall into...
或是会掉到你们身上的东西
or that can fall on you...
或是...
or...
总之要小心
Or just look out!
我还想要...
And I also just want to...
我只想告诉你们...
I just want to tell you all that...
麻烦事  我得去博物馆忙上几个小时
Okay. I have a problem. I have to go into work for a few hours.
有一些小孩大闹智人展厅
Some kids messed up the Homo sapien display.
怎么个闹法
What did they do?
他们将名字涂改得只剩"Homo"(即同性恋)
They painted over the word "sapien, " for one thing.
然后又把人偶重新排列  这个就不说了
Then they rearranged the figures. Let's just leave it at that.
要我帮你照顾本吗
So do you want me to watch Ben for you?
我正要拜托你呢  谢谢
Yes. That's what I was gonna ask. Thank you.
等一下  让我来如何
Wait, hello! What about me?
你  你想照顾本
You? You want to watch Ben.
太好了  我拜托莫妮卡是因为
Yes! That would be great! You know I just asked Monica
我知道她的生活很空虚
because I know how empty her life is.
罗斯
Hey, Ross.
我有个科学问题
I got a science question.
如果智人
If the Homo sapiens were,
真的是"同志"的话
in fact, "homo" sapiens...
他们是因为这个才绝种的吗
is that why they're extinct?
乔伊  智人就是人
Joey, Homo sapiens are people.
我没有批评的意思
Hey, I'm not judging.
小本  你看  汤匙
Look, Benny. Spoon!
汤匙
Spoon!
快看  知道吗  我看他觉得很无聊
Come on. All right, you know what? I think he's bored.
来吧  本  要不要玩坐飞机
Here. Ben, you wanna play the airplane game?
要不要玩给瑞秋看  过来
You wanna show Rachel? Come here.
你想玩好玩的吗  来吧
You wanna do something fun? Okay.
谁最勇敢  你最勇敢了  是的
Who's so brave? You're so brave! Yes, you are.
-你最勇敢了  -没事了
- You're so brave. - You're okay.
他没事  把他放下
He's fine. He's fine. Let's just put him down.
宝贝  过来  你好乖
Come here, babe. Yes, you're such a good boy.
你怎么可以撞到他
How could you do that to him?
罗斯很信任我  他会怎么说
Ross trusted me! What's he gonna say?
他不会说什么  因为我们不会告诉他
He's not gonna say anything, because we're not telling him.
-不会吗  -不会
- We're not? - No, we are not.
这样好  我喜欢
All right, I like that.
你没事  你没事  没事对吗
So we're okay. We're okay, we're okay aren't we?
不  你有事  这里肿起来了
No, we're not okay, we're not okay. There's a bump. There's a bump.
什么肿起来
What bump?
天哪  把它压下去  压下去
Oh, my God! Well, push it in! Push it in!
我不能把它压下去
I cannot push it in!
-好  我们得分散注意力  -好
- Okay, we're gonna need a distraction. - Okay.
-就是这样  -好
- That's it. - Okay.
-我知道了  -好的
- I got it! - Okay.
罗斯一走进来
The second Ross walks in that door...
你就拉他进房间
I want you to take him back to your bedroom,
使出浑身解数
and you do whatever it is you do...
让他快活
that makes him go wee!
或者
Or...
我们也可以帮他戴帽子
we could put a hat on his head.
帽子  没错
A hat! Yes!
-我们需要帽子  -需要帽子
- We need a hat! - We need a hat.
要去哪里找小帽子
Where are we gonna find a tiny little hat?
我去拿雨天小熊
I'll get Rainy Day Bear!
因为他有办法吗
Because he'll know what to do?
天哪  你真是天才
Oh, my God. You're a genius!
好像缝死了
God, it's kind of sewn on though.
-拿来  -好
- Give it. Give it. - Okay.
今天这里真是血腥啊
It's just like a bloodbath in here today!
等一下...
Hey, hold on a second. Hold on a second.
你觉得这串珍珠漂亮吗
Do you think these pearls are nice?
我比较喜欢山地车
I'd really prefer a mountain bike.
珍妮斯的生日快到了  我想送她特别的礼物
Janice's birthday is coming up. I wanna get her something special.
-陪我进去  -慢着
- Come in here with me. - Wait!
你想来点特别的  送花嘛
You wanna get her something special? Get her flowers.
送糖  送口香糖  女生都喜欢口香糖
Get her candy. Get her gum. Girls love gum.
好主意
That's a good idea.
亲爱的珍妮斯  祝你生日快乐得冒泡
"Dear Janice: Have a Hubba Bubba birthday. "
我想送一份有意义的礼物
I would like to get her something serious.
有意义是吧
You want something serious.
知道吗  你应该送...
You know what you should do? You should get her one of those...
灌肠检查
barium enemas.
那个有意义得要命
Those are dead serious.
我要进去  你以后永远不要送东西给我
Look, I'm gonna go in here. And you don't buy me anything, ever!
不行  你不能送她珍珠项链
You can't! You can't. You can't buy her pearls.
不行  不行  不行
You just can't. You can't, You can't, you can't!
为什么不行
Why not?
天哪  好吧
Oh, God. Okay.
是这样的
Here's the thing.
是这样的  好了  事情是...
This is the thing. Okay, the thing is...
-是怎样  -好吧
- What is the thing? - Okay.
我那天去床垫大王的卖场
I went down to the Mattress King's showroom...
看到珍妮斯在跟她的前夫接吻
and I saw Janice kissing her ex-husband.
什么
What?
在他的办公室里
They were in his office.
她不会亲他的  她跟我在一起
She wouldn't do that. She's with me.
是真的  我亲眼看到的
I'm telling you man, I saw it.
你看错了  你错了
Well, you're wrong. Okay? You're wrong.
我没有看错
I'm not wrong.
我也希望我看错了
I wish I was.
对不起
I'm sorry.
现在觉得送灌肠检查不错吧
Bet that barium enema doesn't sound so bad now.
穿整套比较不奇怪
It just makes more sense as an ensemble.
也免得帽子太显眼
Besides, it takes the focus off the hat.
你们还活着  你们还活着
Oh! You're alive! You're alive!
看吧菲比  我不是保证没人会死吗
See Pheebs, I promised you no one would die, didn't I?
待会就知道了
We'll see about that.
借我电话打给我所有认识的人
Can I use your phone to call everyone I know?
你用吧  我们没钱  请便
Sure. We have no money. Go ahead.
你没死啊  好的  再见
Hey, you're not dead! Okay, see you.
莫妮卡
Monica.
天哪  他叫我的名字
Oh, my God! He just said my name!
-你听到了吗  -听到了
- Did you hear that? - Yeah.
莫妮卡  砰
Monica bang!
我听到了
Okay, I heard that.
他是不是说"莫妮卡  砰"
Did he just say, "Monica bang"?
天哪  他要告我的密
Oh, my God! He's gonna rat me out!
莫妮卡  砰
Monica bang!
小乖乖  你不能再说了
Sweetie, you need to stop saying that now.
没什么大不了的  根本不值得一提
It's no big deal. It's not even worth mentioning.
懂吗  我们经常撞来撞去
You see? We all do it all the time.
懂吗  看我的
See? Watch this.
莫妮卡  砰  大家  砰
Monica bang! Everybody bang!
本  砰
Ben bang!
瑞秋  砰
Rachel bang!
砰  瑞秋  砰
Bang, Rachel! Bang!
-很好玩吧  -你看  你看
- Isn't it fun? - Look at that! Look at that!
大家都在砰
We all do it!
-我不撞了  -你还好吗
- Okay, I'm stopping now. - Are you okay?
如果不是床头板  根本不值得
Yeah. You know, if it's not a headboard, it's just not worth it.
我的小宾宾好吗
How's my Bing-a-ling?
我不知道
I don't know.
你说呢
You tell me.
你有话要对我说吗
Anything you want to tell me?
因为要是你...  你应该
Because if you... You should...
你会告诉我的
You would tell me.
你为什么瞪着眼睛
Why are your eyes so wide?
你说呢
You tell me.
也许是因为我和旧情人搞在一起
Maybe it's because I was just fooling around with my ex.
不不不  不不不  那是你
Oh, no no no! No no no! That was you!
我的天
Oh, my God!
-很好  -你怎么知道
- All right! - How did you know?
乔伊说的  他看到你们接吻
Joey told me. He saw you two kissing.
在公园里吗
In the park?
不是  在他的办公室  你们亲了几次
No. In his office. How many kisses were there?
就那两次
Just those two!
为什么...
Why? Why? Why?
为什么接吻  你们不该接吻的
Why was there kissing? There should be no kissing!
对不起  亲爱的  我非常非常...
I'm sorry, honey. I'm so, so...
我非常非常抱歉  我只是...
I'm so, so sorry. I just...
其实是...  我喘不过气来
What happened was I... I can't breathe.
可以给我一个袋子吗
Can you get me a bag or something?
拿去  给你
Here. Here. Here.
-是收据  -给我
- It's the receipt. - I'll take it.
听着  我一定要知道
Look, I've got to know.
你跟我结束了吗
Are you finished with me?
你跟他结束了吗
Are you finished with him?
你还爱他吗
Do you still love him?
你还爱我吗
Do you still love me?
好了  听我说
All right, look...
我需要明确的答案  好吗
I'm gonna need an actual answer here, okay?
你选哪一个
So which is it?
他还是我
Him or me?
我不知道
I don't know.
要是你还活着  请接电话
Okay, if you're alive, you answer your phone!
本  我不会告诉你爸爸
Okay, Ben, I won't tell your daddy
你在晚餐前吃冰淇淋
that you had ice cream before dinner...
你也不能说出那个小小的意外
if you won't tell him about our little bonking incident.
莫妮卡  第一
Monica, number one,
本应该还不懂什么是贿赂
I don't think Ben understands the concept of bribery.
第二  我
And number two, I...
怎么了
What?
你说"第二"
You said, "number two. "
我也说了第一
I also said, "number one. "
我知道
Yeah, I know.
-大家好  -嗨
- Hey, everyone. - Hi!
我的乖儿子好不好
How's my little boy?
他好得很  对吧本
He's perfect. Aren't you, Ben?
他好得不得了
He's never been better.
你们带他去捕鲸了吗
What did you do, take him whaling?
莫妮卡
Monica.
天哪  他说了你的名字
Oh, my God! He just said your name!
太棒了  干得好  本
That's great! Good job, Ben!
莫妮卡  砰
Monica bang!
没错
That's right.
那就是我爆炸的声音
That's what I'd sound like if I exploded.
诅咒解除了  我联络了所有认识的人
The curse is broken! I called everybody I know...
大家都活着
and everyone is alive!
怎么了
What?
丑裸男一动也不动
Ugly Naked Guy looks awfully still.
天哪  我杀了他  我又杀了一个人
Oh my God, I killed him, I killed another one!
诅咒变强了
And this curse is getting stronger too,
那么胖的人也害得死
to bring down something that big.
也许他只是在睡觉
Maybe he's just taking a nap.
错不了的  他从早上开始就没动过
I'm telling you, he hasn't moved since this morning.
我们应该求援
We should call somebody.
怎么说
And tell them what?
说我们一直偷窥的裸男不动了
The naked guy we stare all the time isn't moving?
我们得弄清楚他的死活
We've got to find out if he's alive.
怎么弄清楚  根本没办法
How are we gonna do that? There's no way.
有一个办法
Well, there is one way.
他的窗子开着  我建议
His window's open. I say...
我们戳他
we poke him.
记得我们每次叫中国菜都会留筷子
Hey, you know how we save all those chopsticks...
又不知道为什么吗
for no reason when we get Chinese food?
-是的  -现在有用了
- Yeah. - Well, now we got a reason.
怎么用
What?
我们要做一个很长的探棒
We're fashioning a very long poking device.
好的
All right.
你怎么了
Hey, what's the matter?
我跟珍妮斯谈过了
I talked to Janice.
天哪  她要回到他身边吗
Oh, my God. Is she going back to him?
她不知道
She doesn't know.
她说她两个都爱
Says she loves us both.
今天早上醒来时  我在恋爱
I woke up this morning, I was in love.
我很快乐
I was happy!
觉得那12个安全套买得不冤枉
It serves me right for buying that 12-pack of condoms.
现在连退都不能退  因为收据被她咬烂了
And now I can't even return them, because she choked on the receipt!
你要怎么办
What are you gonna do?
不知道
I don't know.
你会怎么办
You know? What would you do?
我的做法不重要
It doesn't matter what I'd do.
别这样  说嘛
Come on. Come on. Tell me.
好吧  你...
All right, you're...
八成不爱听这种话  但是
probably not gonna want to hear this but...
如果是我  这纯属个人意见
if it was me, and this is just me I would...
我会退出
I would bow out.
什么
What?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
他们有一个孩子
They have a kid together,
你懂吗
you know?
他们是一家人
They're, like, a family.
如果  我不知道
And if, I don't know...
如果他们有机会破镜重圆
if there's a chance they can make that work...
我肯定我不会想当那个障碍
I know I wouldn't wanna be the guy who stood in the way there.
你还好吧
You okay?
要不要来戳裸男
You wanna come poke a nude guy?
他终于睡着了
Well, he's finally asleep.
他头上那个肿包
About that bump on his head...
你确定那是新的吗
Are you sure it's a new bump?
我没有恶意  但我一直觉得
No offense, but I've always thought
本总是满头包
of Ben as a fairly bumpy-headed child.
撞到头也没关系  小孩子经常撞到头
It's okay if he bumps his head. Kids bump their heads all the time.
你第一次照顾他
You know, it was your first time babysitting.
你已经尽力了
For you you did the best you could.
我有尽力
I did!
我知道
I know.
不过你得随时盯着
I'm saying you have to watch them all the time.
我有  我盯得很紧
I did! I watched! I watched!
我眼睁睁看着莫妮卡撞到他的头
I watched Monica bang his head against that thing!
是莫妮卡撞的
Monica did it?
莫妮卡  你有没有发现
Monica, did you notice anything
本今天怪怪的
weird about Ben today?
没有  怎么了
No, why?
我刚才在陪他玩
I was just playing with him,
我们唱了"字母歌"
and we were doing the "Alphabet Song"
他一向很会唱  今天却漏了E和F
which he used to be good at. Suddenly, he's leaving out E and F.
仿佛那两个字母从脑子里掉了出来
It's like they just, I don't know, fell out of his head.
真的
Really?
还有  他走起路来
And also, he's walking...
不太对劲
kind of funny.
似乎左脚
I mean, it's like his left leg
动得比右脚快
is moving a lot faster than his right leg.
他一直在里面  就像这样
Yeah, he's in there, just sort of, you know...
天哪  我害了你的儿子
Oh, my God! I wrecked your baby!
希望你下了地狱还会觉得好玩
I hope it's still funny when you're in hell.
混蛋
You jerk!
你明知我有多爱他
You know how much I love that kid!
莫妮卡  砰  莫妮卡  砰
Monica bang! Monica bang!
我去拿帽子
I'll get the hat.
珍妮斯  我有一件事要告诉你
Janice, I have something I need to tell you.
请你让我说完
And I want you to let me get through it...
因为
because it's...
要说出口并不容易
it's not gonna be easy.
好的
Okay.
我觉得你应该回到盖瑞身边
I think you should go back with Gary.
我不想当拆散家庭的人
I don't want to be the guy that breaks up a family.
我的父母分手  都是那个男人害的
You know, my parents split up, it was because of that guy.
每次见到他  我都会想
Whenever I would see him, I would always think:
"是你害他们不能在一起的"
"You're the reason. You are why they're not together. "
我恨那个人
And I hated that guy.
不管他人有多好  给我爸带来了多少幸福
And it didn't matter how nice he was or how happy he made my dad.
哇
Wow.
没错
Yeah, well.
这样做才对
It's the right thing to do.
你说得对
You're right.
天哪  不过在我说再见之前
Oh, God. But before I can say goodbye...
有件事我一定要让你知道  钱德勒
there's something I really need you to know Chandler.
我对你的感觉
The way I feel about you...
让我终于了解
it's like I finally understand
莱昂纳尔·里奇所唱的情歌的含意
what Lionel Richie's been singing about.
知道吗  我们的一切
You know? I mean, what we have...
就像电影中才有的爱情
it's like movie love.
你是我的心灵伴侣
You're my soul mate.
不敢相信  我们居然无法厮守到老
I can't believe we're not gonna spend the rest of our lives together.
那就不要离开我
Then don't leave me.
什么
What?
忘了我说的话  我是随便说说的  选我吧
Forget what I said. I was babbling. Pick me!
不  你说得对
No, you were right! You were right!
我应该再给婚姻一次机会
I gotta give my marriage another chance.
谁说的
No, you don't!
我说  你应该再给离婚一次机会
I say, you have to give your divorce another chance!
对不起
I'm sorry.
不要走
Don't go.
不  我该走了
No, I gotta go.
别
No.
别  别走
No! No, no.
亲爱的
Honey. Honey.
-大家都在看  -我不在乎
- People are looking. - I don't care.
我不在乎
I don't care!
好了
Yeah, okay. I'm...
我要走了
I'm leaving now.
你走不了  我拿了你的鞋子
You can't leave! I have your shoe!
再见  钱德勒·宾
Goodbye, Chandler Bing.
瑞秋有一双紫红色的
Rachel has those in burgundy.
记住
All right now remember,
这么又大又长的东西很难操作
something this big and long will be very difficult to maneuver.
幸好我有这方面的经验
Fortunately, I have a lot of experience in that area.
专心一点好吗  一个裸男的性命岌岌可危
Can we please focus here? A naked man's life hangs in the balance.
他一定已经死了
I'm telling you, he's dead.
我们会戳到一个死胖子
What we're about to have here is a dead, fat guy on a stick!
各位先生女士  戳吧
All right, ladies and gentlemen, let's poke.
稳着点
Steady.
再高一点
Okay, a little higher.
注意角度
Careful of the angle.
好的  靠近窗户了
Okay, okay. We're approaching the window.
把探针伸进去  伸进去
Thread the needle. Thread the needle.
他还活着  他还活着
He's alive! He's alive!
而我们还在戳他
And yet we're still poking him.
收回探测器  收回探测器
Okay, retract the device! Retract the device!
他好像不太爽
He does not look happy.
轮到他亮出"探针"了
Hey, hey, now he's showing us his poking device.
兄弟  你绝对伸不过来的
Hey, that's never gonna make it all the way over here, buddy!
我会紧紧拥你在怀里
I'll hold you close in my arms.
我无法抵挡你的魅力
I can't resist your charms.
爱人啊
And love...
爱人
Love...
我愿为你做尽傻事
I'll be a fool for you.
毋庸置疑
I'm sure,
你知道我并不介意
you know I don't mind.
我并不介意
No you know I don't mind.
是的
Yes!
你就是我的全世界
You mean the world to me.
我知道
I know.
在你身上
I've found...
我已找到
in you,
无尽的爱
my endless love.
My endless love.
爱
Love.